<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Dedicated to the eternal couple Radha Krishna. Radha Krishna love stories, beautiful illustrations, mantras, Srimad Bhagavatam and Bhagavad Gita teachings and much more...</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why is Krishna blue?</title>
        
          <description>Lord Krishna has been depicted as a baby stealing butter and a charming boy with a flute in his hand and a peacock feather on his head. In all these depictions...</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /why-is-krishna-blue</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/why-is-krishna-blue</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Krishna Story - Why does Krishna wear Peacock Feathers on his head</title>
        
          <description>There's a real story behind Krishna wearing peacock feathers on his head. One afternoon, when Krishna woke up from a rest in the forest while his cowherd friends were still asleep ...</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /why-does-krishna-wear-peacock-feathers-on-his-head</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/why-does-krishna-wear-peacock-feathers-on-his-head</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Story of Birth of Srimati Radharani</title>
        
          <description>There's a story mentioned in the Puranas about the birth of Radha, the eternal consort of Shri Krishna. Radha is considered to be an incarnation of Goddess Lakshmi.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /story-of-birth-of-srimati-radharani</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/story-of-birth-of-srimati-radharani</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Radha Krishna Wallpapers Download</title>
        
          <description>Download the best wallpapers of Shri Radha Krishna for your smartphone/PC/tablet. This section contains a huge collection of Radha Krishna images/wallpapers.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /radha-krishna-wallpapers-download</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/radha-krishna-wallpapers-download</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Krishna Story - When Draupadi met Krishna's Queens</title>
        
          <description>Before the Mahabharat war, Yādavas and many other kings met at Kurukṣetra during a solar eclipse. Krishna also met the residents of Vrindavana after a long time and gave them great joy...</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /krishna-story-when-draupadi-met-krishnas-queens</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/krishna-story-when-draupadi-met-krishnas-queens</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
