<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/</title>
   
   <link>/</link>
   <description>Dedicated to the eternal couple Radha Krishna. Radha Krishna love stories, beautiful illustrations, mantras, Srimad Bhagavatam and Bhagavad Gita teachings and much more...</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   
      
            
               
               
                  <managingEditor>Hanuman</managingEditor>
            
      
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ Hanuman - Shri Radha Krishna ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ Dedicated to the eternal couple Radha Krishna. Radha Krishna love stories, beautiful illustrations, mantras, Srimad Bhagavatam and Bhagavad Gita teachings and much more... ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/assets/images/krishna.png</url>
   <title>Hanuman - Shri Radha Krishna</title>
   <link>/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/author/hanuman/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Radha Krishna Wallpapers Download</title>
	  <link>/radha-krishna-wallpapers-download</link>
		
				
						<author>Hanuman</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-11-29T04:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/radha-krishna-wallpapers-download</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Download the best wallpapers of Shri Radha Krishna for your smartphone/PC/tablet. This section contains a huge collection of Radha Krishna images/wallpapers. We searched the INTERNET for best images of Radha Krishna and found these images that are openly available to everyone.</p>

<p><em>Click on the image to view it or click on the image name to download it.</em></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna4.jpg" download="">Krishna - Playing Flute</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/bal-krishna-with-yashoda-ma.jpg" download="">Krishna Yashoda (i)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna4.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna4.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/bal-krishna-with-yashoda-ma.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/bal-krishna-with-yashoda-ma.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_balaram1.jpg" download="">Krishna and Balaram</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (i)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_balaram1.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna_balaram1.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radhakrishna.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna3.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (ii)</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna.jpg" download="">Little Krishna (i)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna3.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radhakrishna3.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna2.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (iii)</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_yashoda.jpg" download="">Krishna Yashoda (ii)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna2.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radha_krishna2.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_yashoda.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna_yashoda.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna2.jpg" download="">Krishna (i)</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_yashoda.jpg" download="">Krishna (ii)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna1.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna1.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna2.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna2.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna3.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (iv)</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_peacocks.jpg" download="">Krishna (iii)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna3.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radha_krishna3.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_peacocks.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna_peacocks.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_kaliya.jpg" download="">Krishna - Serpent Kaliya</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_brahma1.jpg" download="">Krishna - Brahma</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_kaliya.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna_kaliya.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_brahma1.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna_brahma1.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna2.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (v)</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna1.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (vi)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna2.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radhakrishna2.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radhakrishna1.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radhakrishna1.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna1.jpg" download="">Radha Krishna (vii)</a></th>
      <th style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_vishnu.jpg" download="">Krishna - Vishnu (i)</a></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/radha_krishna1.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/radha_krishna1.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="assets/images/Wallpapers/krishna_vishnu.jpg"> <img src="assets/images/Thumbnails/krishna_vishnu.jpg" alt="" /> </a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Krishna Story - Why does Krishna wear Peacock Feathers on his head</title>
	  <link>/why-does-krishna-wear-peacock-feathers-on-his-head</link>
		
				
						<author>Hanuman</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-11-28T04:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/why-does-krishna-wear-peacock-feathers-on-his-head</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>There’s a real story behind Krishna wearing peacock feathers on his head.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/krishna_friends_1.jpg" alt="krishna_friends_1" /></p>

<p>One afternoon, when Krishna woke up from a rest in the forest while his cowherd friends were still asleep, he decided to wake them up and call the cows who were grazing at a distance by playing his flute.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/krishna4.jpg" alt="krishna_flute_peacocks" /></p>

<p>When Krishna started playing the flute, a melodious raga emerged from its end and its wonderful vibration enchanted the peacocks on and around the Govardhana Hill. Their hearts began to sing and they started dancing with joy. Krishna was pleased with their dance and encouraged them by his kind glances and sweet smiling.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/krishna_peacocks.jpg" alt="krishna_peacocks" /></p>

<p>The peacocks were so full of happiness and gratitude that one of the peacocks went up to Lord Krishna, touched his feet and requested him to dance with them. Krishna happily accepted his request and along with his friends, started dancing with them.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/krishna2.jpg" alt="krishna2" /></p>

<p>The peacocks felt on cloud nine when Sri Krishna danced with them. All the animals of the forest were completely mesmerised by his dancing, unable to move their eyes away from Krishna’s dance. It was so overwhelming, that some peacocks fainted.
The peacocks danced till they grew tired but Lord Krishna went on dancing for days.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/krishna1.jpg" alt="krishna1" /></p>

<p>When he stopped dancing, the king of the peacocks approached Krishna with great humility and asked him to accept his feathers (which were his most prized possession) as ‘Gurudakshina’ for the festival of bliss that Krishna had created. He dropped some of his divine feathers and Lord Krishna lovingly accepted his humble offering, picked up the feathers and placed a few of them on his turban. Since then, Lord Krishna always wears peacock feathers on his head.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Krishna Story - When Draupadi met Krishna's Queens</title>
	  <link>/krishna-story-when-draupadi-met-krishnas-queens</link>
		
				
						<author>Hanuman</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-11-28T04:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/krishna-story-when-draupadi-met-krishnas-queens</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Before the Mahabharat war, Yādavas and many other kings met at Kurukṣetra during a solar eclipse. Krishna also met the residents of Vrindavana after a long time and gave them great joy.</p>

<p>Krishna and his wives then went to meet the Pandavas. He asked Yudhisthira and His other relatives whether they were well. They replied, “My Lord, anyone who has just once consumed through his ears the sweet nectar of Your pastimes can never know misfortune.”</p>

<p>Then Draupadī inquired from Krishna’s wives how the Lord had come to marry them.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/radhakrishna.jpg" alt="radhakrishna" /></p>

<p>Queen Rukmini spoke first: “Many kings, headed by Jarasandha, were intent on giving me in marriage to Shishupala. Thus at my wedding they all stood with bows in hand, ready to support Shishupala against any opponents. But Krishna came and forcibly took me away, as a lion takes his prey from amidst goats and sheep.”</p>

<p>Queen Satyabhama said, “When my uncle Prasena was killed, my father, Satrajit, falsely accused Lord Krishna of murder. To clear His name, Krishna defeated Jambavan, recovered the Syamantaka jewel and returned it to Satrājit. Repentant, my father presented the Lord with both the jewel and myself.”</p>

<p>Queen Jambavati said, “When Krishna entered my father’s cave in search of the Syamantaka jewel, at first my father, Jambavan, did not understand who He was. So my father fought with Him for twenty-seven days and nights. Finally, Jambavan understood that Krishna was none other than Lord Ram, his worshipable Lord. Thus he gave Krishna the Syamantaka jewel, along with me.”</p>

<p>Queen Kalindi said, “To obtain Krishna as my husband, I performed severe austerities. Then one day Lord Kṛṣṇa came to me in the company of Arjuna, and at that time the Lord agreed to marry me.”</p>

<p>Queen Mitravinda said, “Krishna came to my svayamvara ceremony, where He defeated all the opposing kings and took me away to His city of Dvaraka.”</p>

<p>Queen Satya said, “My father stipulated that to win my hand, a prospective suitor would have to subdue and tie up seven powerful bulls. Accepting this challenge, Lord Krishna playfully subdued them, defeated all His rival suitors and married me.”</p>

<p>Queen Bhadra said, “My father invited his nephew Kṛṣṇa, to whom I had already given my heart, and offered me to Him as His bride.”</p>

<p>Queen Lakshmana said to Draupadī, “At my svayamvara, as at yours, a fish-target was fastened near the ceiling. But in my case the fish was concealed on all sides, and only its reflection could be seen in a pot of water below. Several kings tried to hit the fish with an arrow but failed. Arjuna then made his attempt. He concentrated on the reflection of the fish in the water and took careful aim, but when he released his arrow it only grazed the target. Then Krishna fixed His arrow on the bow and shot it straight through the target, knocking it to the ground. I placed the victory necklace on Krishna’s neck, but the kings who had failed raised a violent protest. Lord Krishna valiantly fought them, cutting off the heads, arms and legs of many and sending the rest fleeing for their lives. Then the Lord took me to Dvaraka for our lavish wedding.”</p>

<p>Queen Rohini, representing all the other queens, explained that they were daughters of the kings defeated by Bhaumasura. The demon had held them captive, but when Krishna killed him He had released them and married them all.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Why is Krishna blue?</title>
	  <link>/why-is-krishna-blue</link>
		
				
						<author>Hanuman</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-11-27T05:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/why-is-krishna-blue</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Lord Krishna has been depicted as a baby stealing butter and a charming boy with a flute in his hand and a peacock feather on his head. In all these depictions, there’s one common link though: the blue colour of his skin.</p>

<p>There are different theories to add on why Lord Krishna is bluish in Colour.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>One belief is that when <strong>Demon Putna</strong> tried to kill baby Krishna by her <strong><em>poisoned milk</em></strong>, Krishna didn’t die, instead, his skin became blue.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishna_putna_vadh.jpg" alt="Krishna - Putna Vadh" /></p>

    <p>Another belief is when Krishna was defeating the <strong>Five-headed snake Kaliya</strong>, some of his poison affected him and turned his colour blue.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishna_kaliya.jpg" alt="Krishna and Kaliya" /></p>

    <p>The same theory is floated to explain blue throat <strong>(Neelkanth) of Lord Shiva</strong>, who is believed to have drunk the poison to save the world from destruction at the time of <strong><em>Samudra Manthan</em></strong>.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/shiva_poison.jpg" alt="shiva_poison" /></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Etymologically speaking, the <strong>Sanskrit word ‘Krishna’</strong> means <strong><em>black or dark</em></strong>. At times, it is also translated as “<strong>all attractive</strong>”.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/radha_krishna1.jpg" alt="radha_krishna1" /></p>

    <p>Sanatana Dharma (Hindu religion) believes in symbolisms and the blue colour is a symbol of the <strong>infinite and the immeasurable</strong>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Another theory refers to <strong>Vishnu implanting two hairs</strong>, one black and the other white in <strong>Devaki’s womb</strong> which miraculously got transferred to <strong>Rohini</strong>’s and as a result, from the black hair Krishna tool birth, with a dark skin, and from the white hair his brother Balarama.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishna_balaram1.jpg" alt="krishna_balaram1" /></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Some are of the opinion that the bluish tinge in Lord Krishna’s skin is not the colour of the material body but the <strong>eternal spiritual body of the Lord</strong> that emits a <strong>blue aura</strong>.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishna_brahma1.jpg" alt="krishna_brahma1-1" /></p>

    <p>According to <strong>Bhagavad Gita</strong>, the blissful form of Lord Krishna is <strong>visible only to pure devotees</strong>. He may have bewildered the non-devotees, but those who offered pure devotional service to Him had always seen Him in his blue blissful form.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Another belief is that Lord Vishnu, because of his <strong>association with water</strong>, is depicted blue; therefore, all his incarnations including Krishna, are shown as such. In Sanatana Dharma, those who have the <strong>depth of character and the capacity to fight evil</strong> are depicted as blue skinned.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishna_incarnations.jpg" alt="vishnu_by_mxblizzzzzzz-d9jte51" /></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The theory of the blue colouring of Krishna goes to the fact that the <strong>Creator has given the maximum of blue to nature</strong> i.e. the sky, the oceans, the rivers and lakes. The deity who has the qualities of <strong>bravery, manliness, determination, the ability to deal with difficult situations, of stable mind and depth of character</strong> is represented as blue coloured.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishna_vishnu.jpg" alt="krishna_vishnu" /></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The blue colour of Lord Krishna embodies the <strong>vastness of his character</strong>… the <strong>depth of his vision</strong>… the unfailing <strong>timeliness of his deeds</strong>.</p>

    <p><img src="assets/images/krishnavishnu.jpg" alt="krishna_universe" /></p>

    <p>The blue colour of Lord Krishna encompasses the <strong>whole cosmos</strong>. In spite of millions of glowing stars in the sky, universe or galaxy is blackish i.e beyond our vision. It appears <strong>blue in the day due to sun rays</strong> but in fact, it is <strong>black and infinite</strong>. Imagine how vast our universe is So Krishna’s colour is like the infinite universe.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Story of Birth of Srimati Radharani</title>
	  <link>/story-of-birth-of-srimati-radharani</link>
		
				
						<author>Hanuman</author>
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-11-27T04:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/story-of-birth-of-srimati-radharani</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>There’s a story mentioned in the Puranas about the birth of Radha, the eternal consort of Shri Krishna. Radha is considered to be an incarnation of Goddess Lakshmi. Goddess Lakshmi was hesitant to take birth on Earth before the birth of Lord Vishnu as Shri Krishna. Lord Vishnu tried to convince her but she didn’t want to appear on Earth while Vishnu was still in Vaikuntha Lok. She finally agreed upon the condition that after her birth, she will open her eyes for the first time only when Krishna appears before her. Vishnu agreed to this condition. The day of her appearance on the Earth is known as Radhashtami.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/radha_on_lotus.png" alt="radha_on_lotus" /></p>

<p>On a half-moon night in the month of Bhadra, Vrishabhanu Maharaja went to the bank of the river Yamuna at around noon to take a midday bath. At that moment he saw a huge lotus floating on the water with a golden aura as bright as a thousand suns emanating from it. When Vrishabhanu went closer to the lotus, he saw the most beautiful and radiant form of a baby girl lying within the petals of the lotus. Vishabhanu was happy to see the baby girl and took her home. His wife Kirtida was delighted when she saw the beautiful baby and immediately arranged for all kinds of religious rites to be performed and donated thousands of cows to the Brahmanas. He and his wife named the baby girl Radha.</p>

<p>Soon they noticed that Radha is not opening her eyes. Vrishabhanu and his wife feared that their baby girl was perhaps blind from birth. At that time, Narada Muni appeared and advised him to make arrangements for a lavish birth celebration and sent out invitations to all the residents of Raval and Gokula and especially to his dear friend Nanda Maharaja and his family.</p>

<p><img src="assets/images/radha_krishna_cot-1.jpg" alt="radha_krishna_cot-1" />nees. He crawled up to the cot in which Radhika was lying and pulled Himself up and looked in and His gaze fell upon the beautiful moon-like face of baby Radhika. At that moment, Srimati Radharani’s eyes fluttered and opened wide and blossomed like lotuses for the very first time and looked directly at Krishna, who was the first person that She had ever seen. It seems that she did not want to see anything of this world, only the form of Sri Krishna. Vrishabhanu and Kirtida were overjoyed to find out that their beloved daughter Radhika, was not blind after all. Everyone was delighted.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
